大家吼，我是《每日宇航员》频道的Tim Dodd
Hi, it's me, Tim Dodd, the Everyday Astronaut.
我2013年开始就在节目里穿着这件有股怪味的毛子高空飞行服了
I've owned this horrendously smelly and well-worn Russian high-altitude flight suit since 2013.
你要问我为啥买这东西，我只能回答你无可奉告
Why did I buy it? Well, I have no idea.
就算它有一次差点杀了我
After it almost killed me
我还是穿着它环游了世界还拍了很多酷炫的照片
I still continued to take it around the world with me to take whimsical photographs.
而录节目的时候它简直就是我的负担
And now, it's basically the bane of my existence.
尽管我对这件沙雕衣服又爱又恨
Then although I have a love-hate relationship with this stupid thing,
我还是不知道它在紧急失压时是如何工作的
I do question how well would it actually work in the event of a sudden spontaneous decompression.
所以我觉得我该研究研究真正的宇航服并试穿一下
So, I think it's time I check out a real spacesuit, try it on
决定是否把这件收好吃灰，然后了解一哈某款蓝色的宇航服
and see if it's worth hanging up the old worn spacesuit for something a little more blue.
走你！
Let's get started!
欢迎来到德州休斯敦，NASA约翰逊宇航中心
Welcome to Houston, Texas, home of NASA's Johnson Space Center
这里我将给你们看些一颗赛艇的好东西
and I'm here to show you guys something really exciting.
波音请了我和我的团队来这里了解一下美国的新一代航天服
Boeing flew me and my crew out to check out one of America's next spacesuits.
这是全新的两件宇航服之一
This is one of two brand new spacesuits
NASA新一代宇航员将穿着它在2019年前往太空
that a new generation of astronauts will be wearing to Space in 2019.
前不久NASA刚刚公布首批商业载人飞行首飞乘组
In case you missed it, NASA just announced who will be flying on these first Commercial Crew flights,
波音和太空叉都在比谁的飞船、发射场、航天服先准备好
and both Boeing and SpaceX are racing to get their spaceships, their launch sites, and their spacesuits ready
让美国人重返太空
to return humans to Space from US soil.
虽然我本人没经过任何航天方面的训练（我觉得玩KSP不算）
Despite having virtually zero training, since I doubt playing lots of Kerbal Space Program counts,
波音还是邀请我体验他们最先进的宇航服
I've been asked to check out Boeing's super advanced spacesuit.
在期待了很久之后，我终于穿上了宇航服的内衬
After much anticipation, it's time to put on some space underwear.
红色牌子上写 限制区域 闲人免进
黄色牌子上写 乘组更衣室只供宇航员使用 此区域正在被监控
我真幸运呀，我现在应该算官方钦点宇航员了吧
Well, lucky for me, I guess I'm now officially considered an astronaut.
太空忍（沙）者（雕）！
Space ninja!
宇航服时间！液！
Spacesuit time! Yeah!
简直帅呆了！太……
This is awesome! This is so...
我们能换一件吗？
Can we switch suits?
有没有机会……
Is there a chance that...
能让我花钱把这买下来呢？
Like how can I please just purchase one of these?
这和我想象中的21世纪的宇航服差不多
Yeah, this is what I think of when I think of a 21st century suit,
各种东西变小变轻
like something actually lightweight and small.
在了解更多有关宇航服的信息之前
Before I could prod too much at the suit,
波音的飞行乘组操作与测试工程师
Boeing's flight crew operations and test engineer,
KKM要先来给我们补补课
Kavya Kamal Manyapu, came over to answer all my questions,
就在这时我发现了什么
and that's when I noticed something.
等下，我发现……你快来看看这个！
Wait, I just read... Come here, look at this!
我勒个去！
Holy crap!
标签上印着“天际线飞船宇航员”
飞船图标下方是频道名“每日宇航员”
你们……天啊……流批！
You guys! Look at that! What!
你们快把我感动哭了，太牛逼了
You guys are gonna end up making me cry here. That's amazing!
哭吧，我们是见得多了
We get that a lot, so you can cry.
你这还有人哭？
You have people weeping?
我们的航天服是有多年宇航服设计经验的David Clark设计的
Our spacesuit is built by David Clark that have many several years of experience in actually building spacesuits
他参与了阿波罗工程开始到之前的航天飞机任务
starting from Apollo and even the recent Space Shuttle.
就是宇航员穿的橙色的那件——
What you see the orange suits that the astronauts wear--
嗯，就是“南瓜装”嘛
The pumpkin suit, lovingly called.
我们这里的设计叫“软兜帽”
So, we have what's called a soft-hood.
你的那件高空飞行服脖子上有个圈对吧
对，老难受了
You have a neck ring on your spacesuit
Yes, it's the worse thing in the entire world.
想象你穿着这个，就像个兜帽一样
Imagine wearing this, it's like a hoodie.
哇天啊
Oh, my gosh!
所以这就很方便穿脱
So, it's like really easy to don and doff.
Doff是个词？
Doff is a word?
是的
Doff is a word.
刚来这么一会就学到这么多
I'm learning so much already.
但这仅仅是开始
But that was just the beginning.
我发现这件衣服比上一代轻了40%
I found out the suit is 40% lighter than all previous generation suits.
尽管衣服变轻，而且使用的是更方便的拉链式头盔
Despite being lightweight and featuring that easy to zip helmet,
这件衣服却能承受内部3.5PSI的压强(24kPa)
the suit can hold an internal pressure of 3.5 PSI
大约相当于一万米或者三万四千英尺高度的气压
which is the same amount of air you'd have at 10,000 meters or at 34,000 feet in altitude.
更厉害的是手套在完全充气以后仍能保证灵活性
And most impressively, the gloves maintain their dexterity even when fully inflated, as well.
这是很难做到的
That's the challenge.
航天服手套的设计是极难的，里面有很多灵活设计
They actually say that the gloves are the hardest thing to design, and these look really, really slick.
这……你看它多薄啊
This is... Look at how thin they are.
你们见没见过阿波罗里的舱外宇航服
You guys have probably seen like the shots of Apollo gloves.
那大老粗手指
Those EVA suits have these huge, crazy, puffy fingers,
简直天壤之别，太厉害了
and this is the exact opposite of that. That's amazing.
不过当然我要说明一点
But here's where I should offer up some quick clarification.
这是舱内宇航服
This is a flight suit,
只在飞船内部穿的
which is really only worn inside a spacecraft,
比如飞往空间站途中与返回地球途中
like when you actually fly to the International Space Station or return home.
宇航员还是需要全套舱外宇航服
Astronauts will still have to wear a full extravehicular activity suit
舱外航天服自带生命保障系统与冷却系统
which have their own life-support systems and cooling systems built in
供他们太空行走时使用
if they need to go on a spacewalk
而波音这件替换的是橙色的飞行服
but what this replaces is that orange shuttle aero flight suit.
看看南瓜装有多臃肿吧
And just look at how bulky that thing was.
是不是有种年轻人穿宽松衣服的潮流的感觉
I guess that's about how baggy clothes were back then anyway.
David Clark还和Reebok合作设计了这个
David Clark has partnered with Reebok to come up with this design.
真的很轻
It's really lightweight.
我滴个乖乖这也太轻了
Oh my, this is... When you say really lightweight, you're not kidding.
轻得有点过分了
This is crazy lightweight.
敢问这鞋有多重？
How heavy are these, do you know?
2磅（0.9千克）
Two pounds.
-每个2磅？  -每双
- Two pounds each? - A pair.
每双
A pair.
这双鞋拿着就像是
Both of the these feel about as light
Toms那种鞋一样
as my like normal like Toms even.
我真不知道你们是怎么做到的
I swear I don't know how you make these that light.
纳米碳管，我就猜是这个了！
Carbon nano-tubes. I'm calling it now.
行了，废话少说，穿上试试吧
Okay, enough talking about it. Let's put this thing on.
裤腿穿进去好容易
It slides on so easy.
我其实每次穿我那件衣服都会记着
I might hold the record, actually, for putting on my stupid spacesuit thing.
我大概穿过一百来次
I've probably put that on, what, hundreds of times.
这第一次就已经比我那件还要好穿了
It's already much easier than my suit.
OK，走你
Okay, there we go.
胳膊要这样
Adjust the arms like this.
OK，你最后要做的……
Okay, now what you'll end up doing here...
等我先把这边弄好
Let me get this side squared.
……是向前向下弯腰
Is you are going to bend forward and down
脑袋穿过这里
and through here with your head.
然后慢慢肩膀也跟进去
And slowly roll your shoulders in.
很好
Good.
然后你继续向前慢慢站起，我们将把屁股两侧衣服拉过来
Now you can go ahead and slowly stand up and we'll pull this around your hips.
哇好简单啊
That was so easy.
OK，向前几步
Okay, step forward for me a couple of steps.
OK
Okay.
两臂向两侧伸平
Arm out to the sides.
让我整理下褶皱部分
I'm working the wrinkles out.
感觉如何
How's it feel?
爽灿了
Amazing!
我能雇你们把我的那件旧的换了吗？
看啊！简直不敢相信……
太帅了吧！
感觉胳膊肘这地方……
感觉像是什么也没穿一样
你们看！
看有多灵活
我想说，我真能穿这个在家门口遛弯
I mean, I could actually wear this around the house.
我跟你讲我的经历
And I'll tell you from experience,
我曾经穿我那件衣服整整八小时
I've worn my suit for like eight hours at a time,
简直炼狱一般
and it's the worst thing ever.
但这件，我能穿几个礼拜
I could do this for weeks.
我只要把我房子卖了
I'll just sell my house,
因为这和一个房子差不多了
'cause this is basically like your own little house,
一个移动的房子
a mobile house.
我今天就住这里了，不脱了
I'll just live in this from now on.
快穿好啦
There you go.
这种兜帽式头盔无法在冲击发生时提供足够的保护
The hoodie helmet itself doesn't offer much for crash protection,
所以宇航员还要戴一个内部头盔
so astronauts will wear a beenie that has a small built-in helmet pad
其上还装有通讯系统，用于与他人、地面控制中心交流
as well as the communications system to speak with each other and ground control.
双麦克风！
Dual microphones.
小甜甜布兰妮得嫉妒死我
Britney Spears would be very jealous.
这栗子不太好？
Is that a bad reference?
谁穿得更潮一点？
Who's the more modern?
嘎嘎得嫉妒死我！
Lady Gaga would be very jealous.
这也不好，嘎嘎也不用这些东西
No, but she doesn't use one of those things.
谁还用？
Who else uses?
JB？
Bieber?
爱谁谁吧
I don't know.
反正那些穿成像这样的名人
Insert famous person that has one of these.
肯定都嫉妒死我了
They're jealous right now.
我现在穿着全世界最先进的宇航服
I'm wearing the most advanced spacesuit in the world
还有俩麦克风，我好兴♂奋呀
and I'm excited about two microphones.
我的天！
Oh, my gosh!
这就行了？
That's it?
是的
That's it.
穿戴好容易啊
It goes on so easy.
看啊
Look at that.
请把手臂伸直
Can you reach out completely?
很好
Good.
OK，网友们，能给我众筹一件吗？
Okay, internet, who wants to help me buy one of these?
因为——
Because--
这尺码挺合身的
That's a pretty good length for you.
——我现在就想要一件！
I need one of these right now.
我天下无敌啦！
I have all the power in the world!
MDZZ
太爽了！
This is so great!
你看我牛逼不？
Do I look as cool as I feel?
你看我是不是超级牛逼？
Do I look 10 times cooler than I feel?
因为现在就感觉我贼牛逼
'Cause I feel about as cool as it gets right now.
在他们发现之前我能跑多远？
How far could I get before they've noticed I ran away?
我的车停在两百米远的地方
The car is 200 yards that way.
我觉得我跑的比谁都快
I think I can sprint pretty fast,
然后我们直接开车逃跑
and then we can drive out.
不知道保安的车能开多快
I don't know how fast the security cars are.
我们有辆五菱宏光，我觉得胜算很大
We have a Camry with a four cylinder. I think we got pretty good odds.
在和波音媒体经理一阵谈判之后
After some intense negotiations with Boeing Social Media Manager,
我突然发现自己开始尬舞了起来
I find myself suddenly breaking into some pretty fantastic dance moves.
为了给广大鬼畜爱好者无限想象空间
And just to make this 10 times better,
我决定此处不放任何音乐
I'm going to leave out any music,
你们接下来听到的声音都是麦克风记录的衣服摩擦的声音
so all you hear is the awkward rustling of the microphone against the spacesuit.
别这样，这段掐了别播吧
Wait, no! You're not gonna ruin me now.
看我这样嘚瑟你们可能会问我热不
And here's where you might be asking is this suit hot?
好吧，尬舞这么久之后
Well, after dancing around in it for far too long,
讲道理是有点热
yes, it does get a bit hot,
但幸运的是，宇航服可以连接到通风设备上
but luckily, the suit has an option of being hooked up to ventilation.
我一直期待这个
That's actually what I've always wanted.
我那样尬舞其实是故意的
This is all a big ploy
就是为了体验一下宇航服的通风系统怎么样
'cause I've always wanted to see what ventilation feels like in a spacesuit
我之前在我那件里都快热熟了
'cause I'm used to cooking alive in spacesuits,
而我现在也热得不行
so this is nothing new.
所以我要亲自体验一下
So I'm actually gonna feel
宇航服连上通风是什么感觉
what it's like to have air circulating in a spacesuit.
感觉到循环的气流了吗？
Feel the air circulating?
嗯感觉到了
感觉就像我的私人独享空调
讲真我的确没必要脱了
我希望你们也不会强行让我脱
现在设备都全了
空调系统
我只要在膝盖口袋里放些饮料
我就可以住这里了
好吧，严肃地说
Okay, but in all seriousness,
如果你看不懂我的笑容的话
if you can't tell by my smile,
穿这件宇航服感觉很特别
wearing this spacesuit really feels special,
这就是我所有的感觉
and that's when it all sunk in.
感觉离2011年宇航员最后一次爬进航天飞机已经过了超级久
It feels like it's been forever since we last saw astronauts climb inside the Space Shuttle in 2011
当时他们还穿着鲜艳臃肿的橙色宇航服
wearing those iconic and bulky orange suits.
特别有时代感
It feels like a thing of the past.
但这件，真的很有21世纪的感觉
But this, this really feels 21st century,
更新、更高科技、更轻
new, high-tech, lightweight,
专为新一代太空探索而准备
and truly ready for a new generation of Space explorers.
不，不要……我又穿上这件旧的了
No, no, I'm back in this stupid thing! No!
好吧，讲真，我要马上把这身行头换掉
Okay, seriously, I'm going to replace this thing soon.
穿过之后才知道波音的新宇航服有多好
That made me realize just how much better I could actually have it.
如果你想知道我那件衣服的由来
If you wanna know why I even have this spacesuit or how I got it,
记得看看这个视频，里面我解释了整个荒诞的来龙去脉
be sure and check out this video where I explain that whole ridiculous story.
在下期视频里我将带你进入天际线飞船和训练模拟机
In an upcoming video, I'm going to take you inside a Starliner and the training simulator
让你更深入了解即将到来的商业载人航天项目
to help you learn even more about the upcoming Commercial Crew Program.
感谢波音能给我们这次深入了解的机会
Thanks to Boeing for sending us down there to check out everything.
我经常这样讲
I say this often,
辣鸡波音吃枣药丸！！！
不要站队互喷引战
I am not a big fan of picking teams.
因为我只站在“探索宇宙”这一队！
I'm team Let's Explore Space!
而我也要告诉你
But if you couldn't tell by my face,
我真的很开心
I really had an amazing time.
所以，感谢大家
So, thank you.
如果还有谁想让我了解你们的宇航服和飞船的话
If there's anyone else out there that wants me to check out their spacesuit or upcoming spaceship,
疯狂暗示太空叉
请立即联系我
hit me up,
我帮你们debug！
I definitely got the bug.
另外我真的要好好感谢我的Patreon赞助们
I owe a huge thanks to my Patreon supporters
还有充电的同学们
让我不必用爱发电来做视频
for helping make videos like this and all other content possible.
为了答复你们的支持
As a thanks to those who support this show,
我现在要在每100位赞助者中抽奖
I'm now doing giveaways every 100 patrons.
奖品内容是这些航天材料，比如航天飞机的一部分
It'll always be some kind of lone Space material like this pieces of Space Shuttle.
所以想得到这些硬核太空收藏品的话
So if you want some chance to win some actual flown Space hardware
或者想去我们Reddit特别子版块的话
or want to hang out in our exclusive Subreddit
或者想进我们特别Discord频道的话
or our exclusive Discord channel,
请立即去下方链接赞助我们
head on over to patreon.com/everdayastronaut.
非常感谢！
Thank you.
而在刷无聊的B站之余
And while you're out there on the grand dull internet,
还可以去我自己的网站，链接见下
head on over to my website, everydayastronaut.com,
里面有所有未来所有火箭发射的预告
where you can find Prelaunch Previews of all upcoming rocket launches.
这样你们就再也不用追着屁股在推特问我
That's right, you finally don't have to ask me
下次发射是什么时候什么载荷呀
what's gonna happen on this upcoming mission on Twitter.
你可以直接去我的网站就能查到
You can go there to my website and you can find out,
“这发回收吗？”
"Are they gonna land this one?"
“这发整流罩回收吗？”
"Is this one gonna recover a fairing?
“这发是打什么轨道呀？”
"Where is this mission going to?
“这发咕到啥时候呀？”
"When does it launch?"
所有这类问题都有答案
All the things you need to know in one easy to find place,
而网站里还有我的网店链接
and then while you're there, head on over to my shop
看看我最新的酷炫T恤
and check out my new awesome shirts like this.
上面印着F-1发动机哦！
F-1 Engine can be on your chest.
再次重复下网址
everydayastronaut.com
感谢各位
Thanks everybody. That does it for me.
字幕翻译给虫
欢迎投币点赞收藏分享转发关注充电
我是《每日宇航员》频道的Tim Dodd
I'm Tim Dodd, the Everyday Astronaut
把太空知识带入寻常百姓家！
bringing Space down to Earth for everyday people.